## SUSEENDHAR LAL

#### Software Engineer

Hello, I'm a Full Stack Developer with more than 2 years of experience in Web development. I Love Creating High Quality Websites And Apps That Use The Latest And Greatest Tools Out There To Maximize UI And UX Quality. I enjoy the process of making a web site/app from start to finish.



- Issuseendharlal@gmail.com
- Chennai, India
- suseendhar.netlify.app
- github.com/suseendharlal96

- +91-8012543335/+91-7904217073
- # 08 August, 1996
- in linkedin.com/in/suseendhar-lal-312709155

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Software Engineer** Object Frontier Software

03/2020 - Present

Chennai

Work Order Management

- I work Front end developer and I take the responsibility of developing user-friendly websites.
- This website is created solely for the purpose of managing all the clients a company has acquired till date.
- It manages the number of resources and cost of the resource as well the in-depth detail of current project status.

## **Junior Software Engineer**Object Frontier Software

03/2019 - Present

Chennai

Project Mangement System

#### Achievements/Tasks

- I work as Front end developer using React and also played an important role in creating REST API's using Nodeis.
- Responsible for creating re-usable and flexible components using React and managing store using Redux.

# **Software Engineer trainee**Object Frontier Software

09/2018 - 03/2019

Chennai

Achievements/Tasks

 Got trained as a software engineer and most predominantly on the user interface and frameworks like Reactjs.

## **SKILLS**

HTML CSS/SCSS

JS

eactJs/Redux

Nodejs

MongoDE

Grap

NextJs

GatsbyJs

VueJs/Vuex

GIT

VSCode

NoSQL

Headless CMS

Firebase

### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

My entire projects portfolio

- All my recent works on various tech stacks
- https://suseendhar.netlify.app/projects

### **EDUCATION**

**BE Computer Science**Rajalakshmi Engineering College

08/2014 - 04/2018

Chennai

# **Primary to Higher Secondary** TVS Matric School

08/1998 - 03/2014

Madurai

## **LANGUAGES**

English

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Limited Working Proficiency

Tamil

Sourashtra

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

## **INTERESTS**

Listening music

Creating mini projects